(soft piano music)
- Hello and welcome to Python for Everybody.
I'm Charles Severance, I'm the author of the textbook
and we're going to do a little bit of code.
If you want to get your hands on the code,
go to the materials website, materials.php,
actually materials.php and download the sample code.
The code that we're going to work on today
is the XML code and we need to be able to talk XML
to work with web services.
And so here's one of the examples from the book,
it's xml1.py.
And so later we'll be pulling XML and JSON from the web,
but for now we're just going to put it
in a triple-quoted string, so data.
And we're going to use a built-in XML parser
in Python called Element Tree.
And when we say import xml-e-tree-element-tree,
as-e-t, this as-e-t gives us basically
a shortcut handle for it.
And so the idea, this is a string,
it has less sends and greater thans,
it looks like structured information and it is,
but really at this point it's only a string.
Now we have to call this e-t from string
to read this and give us back a tree object.
And what it does is this might blow up,
this code might blow up right here
if there was a mistake in it, okay?
And matter of fact, I can probably put a mistake in,
let's see if I can delete this and save it
and run this code, and we'll see that it will blow up.
Right?
And so it blew up here in line eight,
Element Tree blew up,
I mean it blew up in line 12 of the code,
which is right here.
This failed because the line eight
of the XML string was wrong.
So let's put that back in.
So now it's properly formed XML.
So this tree we get back, I name it tree
just because I always name it tree,
but you could name it x.
So the key is tree.find goes and looks for a tag name find
and tree is no longer got less thans and greater thans in it,
it is went and turned these into objects
within objects within objects.
So tree find name says I would like to find the tag name
and that's what this bit is right here
and then .txt.text is going within that
and grabbing that text, okay?
And if we say tree find.email,
then that's going to give us this
and then that's that object and then .get asks
for the contents of the hide attribute,
which is the string yes, okay?
And so if we run this, now that it's fixed,
Python 3.xml1.py, it will pull in and get the name
and the attribute, so it pulled the chuck out
and so you get this object
and then you kind of dive into that object
and so that's xml1.py.
If you've got a tag, you can either get the text
out of the tag or you can get an attribute out of the tag.
So now let's take a look at xml2.py.
Again, we import element tree and we have a tag
and xml's always got to have a single outer tag,
but this time we're going to have, in effect, a list.
Now let's line this up a little better.
There we go, that looks a little prettier.
And so users, the fact that it's users doesn't mean anything
but we often come up with semantically meaningful names
for these things.
Users is going to have, as a children, a list of user tags.
Okay, so the children under user, user under user
and then this has each of these as a tag.
So we want to parse this
and this is a common thing we want to do.
And so again, the first thing we do
is we read the string to just take this.
It's a triple-quoted string going from here to here
and then we're going to, instead of doing find,
which gives us one tag, we're going to do find all
the users tag, the user tag that is a child of users.
And we get back a Python list of the tags,
not of the text, but of the tags.
So there's a one tag and there is another tag.
And so we can do len of that so we can see that we got two.
And then we can write a for loop
and this item is going to iterate through the tags
that are the user tags that are children of users.
So the first time item is going to be this tag,
a tag, remember, and then the second time
is going to be this tag.
And so we can do things like find and get
just like we did with an XML1.
So running this is not too exciting.
Python 3, XML2.py.
You see that there are two users
that comes from this print right here.
There are two users in there.
And the first one, if we go into name
and we go find the text within the name tag within user,
then we get Chuck and then we get the ID which is 001.
So we find the ID within that item
and then we get the text.
And then we look and we grab the x attribute off of that.
And so we see Chuck,
Chuck 001 and two.
And then in the next tag, the for loop continues
and we print that out, okay?
And so that's just a basic run through of the XML
from the chapter in the Python book, okay?
Thanks.
(soft music)
you